Hi, I'm Bobby Larew.
Right now we're going to focus on our legs.
When it comes to strength conditioning, a lot of people think the calves are the most important part of jumping.
They're not.
It's actually this part of your legs right here.
That's why Michael Jordan can jump so well.
So I've got a couple of things that you can do to strengthen your leg muscles.
Alright, first thing and my favorite is just squat jumps.
When you do a squat jump, you want your feet about shoulder width apart.
Okay, you're going to lower yourself down, keeping your back straight, pushing the butt to the floor.
What you're going to do from here is jump.
As you jump, you're just going to squeeze your feet together.
When you come back down to the floor, again, spread the legs.
Okay, I'm going to demonstrate for you.
Second, if you've got a chair around or maybe some stairs, you can do a couple of stair raises.
Very simple. Put your left foot up on the chair or the stair, and all your going to do is push up.
Okay, I would alternate in sets on both these exercises doing three sets of about twenty.
Alright, and those are just a few things you can do to strengthen your leg muscles.